[
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 1,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "The high rate of increase in Java's population is largely due to",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "migration from developed countries",
            "intensive agriculature and fertile soils",
            "increase in job opportunities",
            "increase in mineral production",
            "expansion of manufacturing industries"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 2,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following activities engages the largest percentage of human resources in Africa?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "Agriculture",
            "Mining",
            "Transportation",
            "Manufacturing",
            "Construction"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 3,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following is a measure aimed at controlling world population growth?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "Family planning",
            "Decrease in food production",
            "Migration",
            "Encouraging early marriage",
            "Improving soil quality"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 4,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following is a measure aimed at controlling world population growth?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "Family planning",
            "Decrease in food production",
            "Migration",
            "Encouraging early marriage",
            "Improving soil quality"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 5,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following settlement type is the largest?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "Megalopolis",
            "Agglomeration",
            "Conurbation",
            "City",
            "Town"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 6,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "The world's busiest sea route is the",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "South Atlantic route",
            "Cape route",
            "Panama Canal rote",
            "North Atlantic route",
            "Trans-Pacific route"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 7,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "The world's busiest sea route is the",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "South Atlantic route",
            "Cape route",
            "Panama Canal rote",
            "North Atlantic route",
            "Trans-Pacific route"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 8,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following geographical regions of Nigeria covers one -fifth of the country and has a generally flat surface dotted with granitic hills? The",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "North-Central highlands",
            "Western highlands",
            "North-Eastern highlands",
            "Southern coastland",
            "Cross River basin"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 9,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "The location of iron and steel industry at Ajakuta in Nigeria is best explained by the presence of (l) iron ore at ltakpe (ll) limestone at Ewekoro (lll) river port at Lokoja (lV) coal at Orukpa and Okaba",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "l and ll only",
            "l and lV only",
            "ll and lll only",
            "ll and IV",
            "III and IV only"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 10,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "In what part of the West African coast can a tombolo be found?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 4,
        "options": [
            "Senegal",
            "The Gambia",
            "Guinea",
            "Burkina Faso",
            "Sierra Leone"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 11,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "The major problem facing the utilization of human resources in West Africa is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "soil infertility",
            "houseing for all by the year 2000",
            "unemployment",
            "emigration",
            "inter-regional"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 12,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following best accounts for the high population density in the Nile Valley?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "Conducive climate",
            "Presence of numerous oil fields",
            "Presence of rich alluvial winter",
            "Migration from Europe during winter",
            "Presence of ancient tombs and monuments"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 13,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "In Africa the Mediterranean climate occurs in the",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 4,
        "options": [
            "south eastern coastland",
            "norther part",
            "continental interior",
            "areas around the equator",
            "extreme north and south"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "geography",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 14,
        "year": 1993,
        "question": "Which of the following countries is located within the Horn of Africa?",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "Swaziland",
            "Chad",
            "Kenya",
            "Djiboti",
            "Libya"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    }
]